Werner, Alfred; Papers ger096
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Writings: Monographs of Artists, 1925-1979; Undated; 4
  - Soyer, Moses. Typescript of interview by Werner of Moses Soyer, 1968 (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 15)
  - Soyer, Moses. Clippings, catalogs of exhibits, 1948-1974 (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 16)
  - Utrillo, Maurice. Alfred Werner:Maurice Utrillo. Notes, handwritten, 1953 (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 17)
  - Weber, Max. Correspondence re: research on Weber monograph, 1969-1970 (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 18)
  - Weber, Max. Alfred Werner:Max Weber. Typescripts, 1975 (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 19-20)
  - Weber, Max. Alfred Werner:Max Weber. Photocopies of typescript pages, with numerous corrections, 1975 (Oversized 22, Folder 14)
  - Weber, Max. Alfred Werner:Max Weber. Colorplate descriptions, typescript; also photographs for volume, 1975 (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 21)
  - Weber, Max. Alfred Werner:Max Weber. Proofs, 1975 (Oversized 22, Folder 15)
  - Weber, Max. Alfred Werner:Max Weber. Reviews, 1975 (Box 7 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 1)
  - Weber, Max. Typescripts of short articles on Weber by Werner, Undated (Box 7 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 2)
  - Weber, Max. Notes, handwritten and typed, Undated (Box 7 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 3-4)
  - Weber, Max. Student papers, clippings, 1925-1975 (Box 7 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 5)
- Writings: Articles on Artists, 1903-1979; Undated; 5
  This series contains typescripts, proofs, handwritten and typed notes, a small amount of correspondence, clippings, exhibition catalogs, and photographs pertaining to lexicon, magazine and newspaper articles and book reviews written by Alfred Werner on artists and other personalities. Although most of the typescripts of the articles are Undated, they range from the early 1940s until Werner's death in 1979.
  - A – Artists. Clippings on artists, no writings by Werner present in the collection, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 6)
  - Achiam, 1957; 1 card to Werner (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 7)
  - Adler, Eliahu. Typescript, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 8)
  - Adler, Jankel [Yankel]. Typescripts, notes, clippings, exhibition catalog, 1949-1967; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 9)
  - Agam, Yaakov. Student paper, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 10)
  - Alkara, Abdullah, 1971; 1 L. to Werner (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 11)
  - Alkara, Abdullah. Typescript, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 12)
  - Altdorfer, Albrecht. Typescript, notes, clipping, 1969; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 13)
  - Angelico, Fra. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 14)
  - Antokolski, Mark. Notes, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 15)
  - Ardon [-Bronstein], Mordecai. Correspondence re: Ardon, 1967-1974; 1 L. from Ardon to Werner (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 16)
  - Ardon, Mordecai. Typescripts of articles; notes; photographs of artwork, 1969; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 17)
  - Ardon, Mordecai. Clippings, exhibition catalogs, 1948-1974 (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 18)
  - Aronson, David. Typescript, notes, catalogs, clippings, 1956-1979; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 19)
  - Aronson, Naum. Typescript, notes, clipping, 1960; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 20)
  - Arp, Jean. Typescript (review), clipping, 1977; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 21)
  - Audobon, James. Typescript, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 22)
  - B – Artists. Clippings on artists, no writings by Werner present in the collection, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 23)
  - Bacon, Francis. Typescripts, clipping, 1972; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 24)
  - Bak, Samuel. Notes, clippings, catalogs, photographs, 1965-1969; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 25)
  - Bakst, Leon [Lev Rosenberg]. Typescripts, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 26)
  - Bakst, Leon. Notes, clippings, 1973-1977; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 27)
  - Baskin, Leonid. Typescripts, published articles, notes, 1964; 1969; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 28)
  - Baskin, Leonid. Catalogs, clippings, 1961-1974 (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 29)
  - Baudelaire, Charles. Typescripts, published article, notes, clippings, 1955-1969; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 30)
  - Bazille, Frédéric. Notes, clippings, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 31)
  - Beardsley, Aubrey. Typescript, notes, clippings, 1966-1967; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 32)
  - Beckmann, Max. Typescripts, notes, clippings, catalogs, 1962-1969 (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 33)
  - Beer-Hofmann, Richard. Typescript, 1978 (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 34)
  - Ben-Haim, Mula. Typescript, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 35)
  - Ben-Zion. Typescripts, interview, 1973; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 36)
  - Ben-Zion. Notes, clippings, catalogs, 1948-1973 (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 37)
  - Bendemann, Eduard. Notes, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 38)
  - Berenson, Bernard. Typescripts, published article, 1960; Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 39)
  - Berenson, Bernard. Clippings, 1949-1963 (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 40)
  - Berger, Rene. Typescript, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 41)
  - Berman, Sarah. Proof of article by Werner, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 42)
  - Bernini, Gian Lorenzo. Typescript, Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 43)
  - Bertoia, Harry. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 7 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 44)
  - Berger, Rene. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 1)
  - Berman, Sarah. Proof of article by Werner, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 2)
  - Bernini, Gian Lorenzo. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 3)
  - Bertoia, Harry. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 4)
  - Bihalj-Merion, Otto, 1967; 1 L. from Otto and Lisa B-M to Werner (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 5)
  - Birnbaum, Uriel. Typed "Lebenslauf", clipping, 1958; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 6)
  - Bishop, Isabel. Notes, typed, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 7)
  - Blaser, Irene. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 8)
  - Bloom, Hyman. Typescripts, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 9)
  - Bloom, Hyman. Notes, clippings, 1954-1968; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 10)
  - Boecklin, Arnold. Typescripts, notes, clippings, 1964; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 11)
  - Bonnard, Pierre. Notes, catalogs, 1956-1963; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 12)
  - Boris, Bessie. Recommendation by Werner, 1962 (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 13)
  - Bosch, Hieronymus. Typescripts (reviews), Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 14)
  - Bouguereau, William Adolphe. Typescripts, notes, clippings, 1922-1974; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 15)
  - Brancusi, Constantin. Typescript, notes, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 16)
  - Braque, Georges. Typescript, clipping, 1960; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 17)
  - Brauer, Erich. Typescripts, notes, clipping, catalogs, 1967-1971; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 18)
  - Browne, Byron. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 19)
  - Brzosko, Wladyslaw. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 20)
  - Burchfield, Charles. Typescripts, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 21)
  - Burliuk, David. Typescripts, published article, clippings, 1966-1967 (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 22)
  - C - Artists. Clippings on artists, no writings by Werner present in the collection, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 23)
  - Caillebotte, Gustave. Typescripts, notes, clippings, photograph, 1968; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 24)
  - Cassatt, Mary. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 25)
  - Castel, Moshe. Typescripts, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 26)
  - Cegla, Rachel. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 27)
  - Cézanne, Paul. Typescripts, notes, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 28)
  - Cézanne, Paul. Clippings, 1927-1967 (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 29)
  - Charlot, Jean. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 30)
  - Clave, Antoni. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 31)
  - Constable, John. Typescript (review), clipping, 1976; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 32)
  - Corinth, Lovis. Typescripts, notes, clippings, 1943-1974; Undated; 1 L. from Thomas Corinth (son of Lovis) (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 33)
  - Corot, Jean-Baptiste-Camille. Typescripts, notes, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 34)
  - Courbet, Gustave. Typescripts, notes, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 35)
  - Courbet, Gustave. Clippings, 1959-1978 (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 36)
  - Cranach, Lucas. Typescript, notes, clippings., 1960-1968; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 37)
  - Crome, John the Elder. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 38)
  - Crystal, Boris. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 39)
  - D − Artists. Clippings on artists, no writings by Werner present in the collection, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 40)
  - da Vinci, Leonardo. Typescripts, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 41)
  - Dali, Salvadore. Typescripts, notes, clippings, 1965-1976; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 42)
  - Daphna, Annette. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 43)
  - Daumier, Honoré. Typescripts, notes, clippings, 1966-1976; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 44)
  - Davidson, Jo. Typescripts, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 45)
  - Davis, Harry. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 46)
  - de Haan, Jacob Meijer. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 47)
  - De Hooghe, Romeyn. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 48)
  - de Stael, Nicolas. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 49)
  - Delacroix, Eugene. Typescripts, notes, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 50)
  - Delacroix, Eugene. Student papers, clippings, 1952-1974 (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 51)
  - Delauney, Robert. Typescript, clippings, 1924-1976 (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 52)
  - Delman, Benzion E. Typescript, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 53)
  - Derain, André. Typescript, notes, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 54)
  - Dix, Otto. 1 L. from Otto Dix. Undated. Typescript, notes, death notice, clippings, 1952-1969 (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 55)
  - Donatello. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 56)
  - Durand-Ruel, Paul. Typescript., Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 57)
  - Duveen, Sir Joseph. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 58)
  - E − Artists. Clippings on artists, no writings by Werner present in the collection, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 59)
  - Eakins, Thomas. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 60)
  - Earl, Ralph. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 61)
  - Elvaiah, Ahron. Typescript., Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 62)
  - Ensor, James. Typescripts, notes, clippings, catalog, 1963-1976; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 63)
  - Epstein, Jacob. Typescripts, published article, 1951; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 64)
  - Epstein, Jacob. Clippings, 1950-1968 (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 65-66)
  - Epstein, Jacob. Catalogs, exhibition materials, 1966-1971 (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 67)
  - Ernst, Max. Typescripts, notes, clippings, 1966-1978; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 68)
  - Ezekiel, Moses Jacob. Typescript, notes, clippings, 1917-1952; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 69)
  - F − Artists. Clippings on artists, no writings by Werner present in the collection, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 70)
  - Fantin, Latour. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 71)
  - Fechenbach, Hermann. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 72)
  - Feininger, Lyonel. Typescripts, printed articles, 1960; Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 73)
  - Feininger, Lyonel. Notes, handwritten and typed, Undated (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 74)
  - Feininger, Lyonel. Hans Hess:Lyonel Feininger, 1961 (Box 8 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 75)
  - Feininger, Lyonel. Catalogs, exhibit materials, 1948-1961 (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 1)
  - Feininger, Lyonel. Clippings, 1954-1973 (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 2)
  - Feniger, Shoshana. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 3)
  - Filmus, Tully. Typescripts, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 4)
  - Forain, Jean-Louis. Typescripts, notes, clippings, 1922; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 5)
  - Freiberger Csato, Eva. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 6)
  - Frenkel, Itzhak. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 7)
  - Frenkel, Vera. Notes, clipping, 1965; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 8)
  - Fried, Otto. Typescript, catalog, 1963; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 9)
  - Friedlander, Isac, 1960; 1 L. from Friedlander to Werner (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 10)
  - Friedrich, Caspar David. Typescript (review), clippings, 1972; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 11)
  - Fusely, Henry. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 12)
  - G − Artists. Clippings on artists, no writings by Werner present in the collection, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 13)
  - Gabo, Naum. Letter and Student paper, clippings, 1958-1968; Undated; 1 L. from Miriam Gabo to Werner (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 14)
  - Gainsborough, Thomas. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 15)
  - Gaudi, Antonio. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 16)
  - Generalic, Ivan. Typescripts, clipping, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 17)
  - Gericault, Jean-Louis-André-Theodore. Typescripts (reviews), Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 18)
  - Gertler, Mark. Typescripts, notes, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 19)
  - Gertler, Mark. Clippings, catalogs, 1957-1973 (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 20)
  - Ghibert, Lorenzo. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 21)
  - Gilboa, David. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 22)
  - Giotto di Bondone. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 23)
  - Gislebertus. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 24)
  - Gisson, Andre. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 25)
  - Glicenstein, Enrico. Typescripts by Werner and others, notes, catalogs, clippings, 1929-1959; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 26)
  - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 27)
  - Gombrich, Ernst. Typescript, clipping, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 28)
  - Gorky, Arshile. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 29)
  - Gottilieb, Maureyey. Transcripts, printed article, notes, clippings, 1962-1978; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 30)
  - Gottschalk, Don. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 31)
  - Goya, Francisco. Typescripts, clipping, 1976; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 32)
  - El Greco. Typescript, partly handwritten, with numerous photographs inserted, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 33)
  - Gropius, Walter. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 34)
  - Gropper, William. Typescripts, notes, clippings, catalogs, 1937-1977; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 35)
  - Grosman, Maurice, 1955; 1L. From Tatyana Grosman to Werner (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 36)
  - Gross, Agnes. Typescript., Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 37)
  - Grosz, George. Typescripts, notes, clippings, exhibition materials, photographs, 1939-1976; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 38)
  - Grunewald, Mathias. Typescripts, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 39)
  - Guggenheim, Solomon Robert, Typescript. clippings, 1978; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 40)
  - H-Artists. Clippings on artists, no writings by Werner present in the collection, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 41)
  - Halpert, Samuel. Notes, clippings, 1922 (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 42)
  - Har-Even, Judith. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 43)
  - Hardie, Martin. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 44)
  - Harriton, Abraham. Notes, exhibit catalog, 1956; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 45)
  - Hart, Solomon Alexander. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 46)
  - Heckel, Erich, 1964; 2 L. from Heckel to Werner (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 47)
  - Heine, Heinrich. Typescripts, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 48)
  - Hertzberg. Rose. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 49)
  - Herzl, Theodor. Typescripts, notes, photograph, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 50)
  - Hicks, Edward. Typescript, notes, clippings, 1975; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 51)
  - Hodler, Ferinand. Notes, clippings, 1973; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 52)
  - Horgarth, William. Typescript (review), clipping, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 53)
  - Holbein, Hans. Typescripts, notes, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 54)
  - Holtz, Itshal. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 55)
  - Holzman, Shimshon. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 56)
  - Homer, Winslow. Typescript (review), clipping, 1973; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 57)
  - Hopper, Edward. Typescripts, clippings, catalog, 1971-1974; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 58)
  - Horowitz, Leopold. Notes, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 59)
  - Horowitz, Nadia. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 60)
  - Ingres, Jean-Auguste-Dominique. Typescripts, notes, clippings, catalog, 1967-1971; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 61)
  - Israels, Issac. Typescript, clipping, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 62)
  - Israels, Jozef. Typescripts, published article, notes, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 63)
  - Israels, Jozef. Student papers, clippings, 1911-1974 (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 64)
  - J-Artists. Clippings on artists, no writings by Werner in this collection, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 65)
  - Jackmann, Sandra. Typescript, Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 66)
  - Janco, Marcel, 1971; 1 L., 1 Ptc. from Janco to Werner (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 67)
  - Janco, Marcel. Typescripts, notes, clippings, catalogs, 1950-1974 (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 68)
  - Jawlensky, Alexei [Alexei Georgiyevich Yavlenski]. Typescripts, notes, clippings, catalogs, 1958-1975 (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 69)
  - Jordaens, Jacob. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 70)
  - Josephson, Ernst Abraham. Typescribts, notes, clippings, 1949-1965; Undated (Box 9 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 71)
  - K- artists. Clippings on artists, no writings by Werner present in the collection, Undated (Box 10 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 1)
  - Kaish, Morton. Recommendation, typed, Undated (Box 10 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 2)
  - Kandinsky, Wassily. Typescripts, clippings, catalogs, 1963-1974 (Box 10 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 3)
  - Kantor, Alfred. Typescript (review), Undated (Box 10 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 4)
  - Karczmar, Simon. Typescript, Undated (Box 10 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 5)
  - Karfiol, Bernard. Notes, Undated (Box 10 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 6)
  - Katz, Anna. Typescript, Undated (Box 10 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 7)
  - Kaufmann, Arthur. Typescript, published article, clipping, catalogs, 1954-1971 (Box 10 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 8)
  - Kaufmann, Isidor. Typescripts. Notes, student papers, clippings, 1967-1974; Undated (Box 10 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 9)
  - Kaz, Nathaniel. Typescript, catalog with article by Werner, Undated (Box 10 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 10)
  - Keyser, Ephraim. Notes, Undated (Box 10 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 11)
  - Kikoine, Michael. Notes, clippings, 1933; Undated (Box 10 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 12)
  - Kirchner, Ernest Ludwig. Typescripts, notes, Undated (Box 10 (5-Writings: Articles on Artists), Folder 13)